<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gunjankholapure.github.io/First-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://gunjankholapure.github.io/First-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-22T08:37:12-05:00</updated><id>https://gunjankholapure.github.io/First-Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Gunjan Kholapure</title><entry><title type="html">MS(R) CSE programme at IITK</title><link href="https://gunjankholapure.github.io/First-Blog/markdown/2020/08/15/MS(R)-CSE-programme-at-IITK.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MS(R) CSE programme at IITK" /><published>2020-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://gunjankholapure.github.io/First-Blog/markdown/2020/08/15/MS(R)%20CSE%20programme%20at%20IITK</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gunjankholapure.github.io/First-Blog/markdown/2020/08/15/MS(R)-CSE-programme-at-IITK.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;msr-cse-programme-at-iitk&quot;&gt;MS(R) CSE programme at IITK&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; :- This article deals with MS(R) CSE programme at IITK. The information contained in this article is according to rules during 2018 MS(R) programme. Things may change in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of information about different programmes in IIT Kanpur can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iitk.ac.in/doaa/data/pgmanual-02Sep2015.pdf&quot;&gt;PG Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS(R) is a relatively new programme started in 2015 at IITK. Since this a relatively new programme and the intake of students is less in this programme, new students generally 
have some doubts regarding it. Below I have mentioned a few points that may help new students in making better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;admission&quot;&gt;Admission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admission to MS(R) program generally requires giving an Interview in all IITs. Students are shortlisted on the basis of their GATE (Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering) scores 
for the admission process. For admission to MS(R) programme in CSE branch at IIT Kanpur in 2018,  students had to clear a coding test and an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difference-between-msr-and-mtech-programme&quot;&gt;Difference between MS(R) and Mtech Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This programme is perfect for students who are interested in doing research in a particular area but are not sure about doing a PhD. Although MTech students also carry out research work, there are some differences in both programmes as listed 
below -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coursework in MTech Programme is more as compared to MS(R) programme. M.Tech students are required to take a minimum of 7 courses while MS(R) students have to do a minimum 
of 4 courses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Mtech programme, students have to take atleast one course from each of the three pools i.e Systems, Application, Theory. There is no such restriction for MS(R) students.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The duration of MTech programme is 2 years while there is no fixed duration of MS(R) programmes. Students generally complete MS(R) programme in 2-3 years time. The 
financial assistanship is however for a period of about two years only in MS(R) programme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS(R) students are also expected to publish a paper although it is not compulsary. MS(R) students can also extend their programme to PhD before second year if they wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;faqs-&quot;&gt;FAQs-&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many students completed MS(R) programme in 2 years?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of 9 MS(R) CSE students enrolled in 2018, four students completed their thesis work in two years while four students have extended thier programme and one has convrted to PhD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">MS(R) CSE programme at IITK</summary></entry></feed>